(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
もっと もっと 上がるよ 空に
Rising higher and higher into the sky,
大きな夏の花
are the giant flowers of summer.
君と眺める夏の花
The Summer Flower I Watch with You
作詞：芳賀峻　作曲・編曲：メリッサ
Lyrics: Shun Haga / Composition & Arrangement: Melissa
Music：メリッサ　Movie：あきまゆ
Music: Melissa / Movie: Akimayu
ふらふら歩く夜の　美味しい香りに誘われて
Drawn by the delicious scents of the night as I wander,
カラコロ響く下駄の音　どこまでも
the clatter of my clogs echoes on and on.
キラキラ輝く屋台の明かりに飛び込んで
Diving into the light of the sparkling festival stalls,
パクパク頬張る真っ赤なイチゴ飴
I gobble down a bright red strawberry candy.
さぁ　パッと　パッと
Now, suddenly, suddenly,
ずっと待ってた
I've been waiting forever.
ほらね　今年も花火が打ち上がる
Look, the fireworks are going off again this year.
さぁ　祭りだ　祭りだ　祭りだ　ワッショイ！
Now, it's a festival! A festival! A festival! Wasshoi!
一　二　の　三　ので声出して
On the count of one, two, three, let's shout!
手と手を繋いで　さぁ行こう
Hand in hand, let's go!
ワッショイ！
Wasshoi!
まだまだ上がるよ
It's still going up
今夜の花火もテンションも
Tonight's fireworks and my excitement too
華やか賑やか見るもの全てが眩しくて
Elegant and lively, everything I see is so dazzling
シャカシャカパカパカ頬張る　食べ歩き日和
Munching and crunching, it's a perfect day for snacking
さあ　パンパカパカパカやって
Now, let's go with a fanfare
クスクス笑わせて
Make me giggle
君の笑顔の花火が打ち上がる
The fireworks of your smile are being launched
さあ　楽しみ祭りだ止まるな
Now, it's a festival of fun, don't stop
ワッショイ！
Wasshoi!
弾けるリズムは最後まで
This bursting rhythm until the end
浴衣も忘れて跳ねるよ
I'll jump and forget about my yukata
ワッショイ！
Wasshoi!
もっともっと上がるよ
It's going higher and higher
空に大きな夏の華
A big summer flower in the sky
みんなー！今日は来てくれてありがとう！
Everyone! Thank you for coming today!
まだまだ始まったばかり！最後まで盛り上がっていってね！
It's just the beginning! Keep the energy up until the end!
綿飴頬張り溶けるよ
Munching on cotton candy, it melts
一瞬輝く時間もかけてよ
Spend that brief shining moment with me
君との思い出溶けない
Memories with you won't melt away
一生消えない宝物
They're treasures that will last a lifetime
祭りだ祭りだ祭りだ
It's a festival, a festival, a festival
ワッショイ！
Wasshoi!
流れる光に照らされて
Illuminated by the flowing light
全てが眩しい思い出
Everything is a dazzling memory
ワッショイ！
Wasshoi!
もっともっと輝け
Shine more and more
君と並べる夏の華
The summer flower blooming next to you
最初から君を好きでいられてよかったなんて空に歌うんだ
I'll sing to the sky that I'm glad I could love you from the start
Fire◎Flower
作詞・作曲: halyosy
Lyrics & Music: halyosy
積み上げた想い　打ち上げる場所
The feelings I've built up, the place to launch them
探し求めて　この街から出た
I left this town in search of it
震える着信　電源を切った
A vibrating call, I turned off the power
燃え出す導火線　誰も止められない
The fuse is burning, no one can stop it
世界の終わりが　今訪れたとしたら
If the end of the world were to come now
全部放り投げて
I'd throw everything aside
二人永遠に一緒なのにね
And we'd be together forever, right?
Like a Fire Flower
僕が消えちゃわないように
So that I don't disappear
火の粉散らせ　夢打ち上がれ
Scatter the sparks, let the dream soar
最初から君を好きにならなきゃよかったなんて
Saying I wish I hadn't loved you from the start
嘘までついて
I even lied like that
慣れない景色　不自然な笑顔
Unfamiliar scenery, an unnatural smile
華やかな祭りと　違ってた
It was different from the lively festival
繰り返す「頑張れ」の声
The repeated voices saying "Do your best"
涙で導火線　消えちゃいそうだよ
It feels like my fuse will be put out by tears
宇宙の始まりが　あの口づけだとしたら
If that kiss was the beginning of the universe
星空は
Then the starry sky
二人がこぼした奇跡の跡
Is the trail of the miracle we spilled
Like a Fire Flower
君が見つけやすいように
So that you can easily find me
雷鳴の如く　夢轟かせ
Let the dream roar like thunder
最初から君を好きにならなきゃよかったなんて
Saying I wish I hadn't loved you from the start
バレてるんだろうな
You probably know I was lying
バラバラな僕ら 姿も形も
We're all scattered, in appearance and form.
それぞれな僕ら 男も女も
Each of us is different, men and women too.
チグハグな僕ら それでも心を
We're all mismatched, but if we could still
ひとつにできたなら
unite our hearts as one...
人生の途中が 線香花火だとしたら
If the middle of our lives were like incense fireworks,
人生の途中が
If the middle of our lives
線香花火だとしたら
were like incense fireworks,
一瞬でもふたり照らす 向日葵の様に
then even for a moment, let's shine together like sunflowers.
一瞬でも ふたり照らす
then even for a moment, let's shine together
向日葵の様に
like sunflowers.
Like a Fire◎Flower いつか夜空に大輪を
Like a Fire◎Flower, one day, into a large flower in the night sky
FIRE◎FLOWER
いつか 夜空に大輪を
one day, into a large flower in the night sky
咲かすその時まで待ってくれ
wait for me until the time I bloom.
最初から君を 好きでいられて良かったなんて
'I'm glad I could love you from the start,'
空に歌うんだ
I'll sing to the sky.
はーい！歌い終わりました、皆さん！
Yes! I've finished singing, everyone!
こんばんはっしょーい！
Konbanwasshoi!
どうも、ホロライブの清楚担当、
Hello, I'm Hololive's 'seiso' (pure) representative,
みんなのアイドル、夏色まつり、まつりですわー！
everyone's idol, Natsuiro Matsuri, or just Matsuri-desu-wa!
ということで、
So,
今回のライブのタイトルはですね、
the title of this live concert is,
夏色 Full Bloom でございます！
'Natsuiro Full Bloom'!
あの、なんか「季節色々」みたいな意味らしいです、
Um, apparently it means something like 'various seasons',
調べた。
I looked it up.
春夏秋冬のね、お花畑、
The flower gardens of the four seasons...
ここに今ひまわりが咲いてると思うんですけど。
I think sunflowers are blooming here now.
いいでしょ？可愛いでしょ？
Isn't it nice? Isn't it cute?
はい、お花畑をテーマにですね、
Yes, with a flower garden theme,
季節の四季折々な感じで、
reflecting the four seasons,
ステージと曲を色々楽しんでもらえたらなーと思いますよ。
I hope you'll enjoy the various stages and songs.
はい！
Yes!
ということで、最初は夏のステージでございました。
So, the first part was the summer stage.
君と眺める夏の花と、
You heard 'Kimi to Nagameru Natsu no Hana'
あと Fire◎Flower を聴いていただきましたけども。
and 'Fire◎Flower'.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
両方こう、花火の曲でね、
Both are fireworks songs,
まつりちゃんぽい、パンパンパン！
very much like Matsuri-chan! Bang, bang, bang!
花火はね、元気なまつりちゃんにぴったりでございますけど。
Fireworks are perfect for the energetic Matsuri-chan.
どうでしたか？
How was it?
良かった？
Was it good?
ありがとうございます！はい！
Thank you very much! Yes!
そしてさっきも触れたんですけど、
And as I mentioned earlier,
ちょっとステージを見てもらいたい。
I want you to take a look at the stage.
どうよ、このひまわりたち。
Look at all these sunflowers.
めっちゃ可愛い。すっごい咲いてるの。
They're so cute. There are so many blooming.
すっごい。何本かは分かんないんですけど。
So many. I don't know exactly how many though.
そしてね、さっきも見たと思うんですけど、
And I think you saw it earlier,
あの花火もね、上がってたでしょ？ヒューって。
but fireworks were also going off, right? Like 'whoosh'.
今も上がる？
Will they go off now too?
ヒュー、わー！綺麗！
Whoosh, wow! So beautiful!
もうね、ちょっと夏は終わってるんですけどもね、
Well, summer is actually ending soon, but
この世界では夏を楽しめるということで、
in this world, we can enjoy summer anytime.
季節自由自在でございます。
The seasons are freely adjustable here.
バーチャルなのでな！
Because it's virtual!
ということで、これからもね、
So, from now on,
春とか、秋とか、冬とかも来ますので、
spring, autumn, and winter will also be coming,
なんのお花が咲くのか予想しながら見ていただきたいなーと思います。
so watch while trying to guess what flowers will bloom.
そして、ライブ前にですね、
Also, before the live,
あの、ダンスの練習動画もね、投稿したと思うんですけど。
um, I believe I posted a dance practice video.
見てくれましたか？はい！
Did you watch it? Yes!
今回ね、ダンス、また頑張ってますので、
I've worked hard on the dance again this time,
あの、たくさん注目してみてくれると嬉しいなーと思います。はい！
so I'd be happy if you'd pay close attention to it. Yes!
はい！
Yes!
メン限用にね、ダンス練習覗き見動画みたいな
It seems like there's also a bonus video for members,
特典も上がってるみたいなので、
like a 'sneak peek at dance practice',
メン限まだ入ってないよーって方は
so for those who aren't members yet,
入ってくれると嬉しいなーと思います。
I'd be happy if you'd join.
メンギフとかも、お願い、
And for membership gifts too, please...
あ、ありがとうございますね！はい！
oh, thank you very much! Yes!
ということで、今回のライブの感想は
Anyway, please tweet a lot of your impressions
「#夏色FullBloom」でたくさん呟いてください。
of this live with the hashtag #NatsuiroFullBloom.
夏色は漢字で、Full Bloom が英語となっております。
'Natsuiro' is in kanji, and 'Full Bloom' is in English.
ということで、次の季節がそろそろ来そうですね。
So, it looks like the next season is about to arrive.
では、行きますよ。
All right, here we go.
次の季節へ、
To the next season,
レッツゴー！
let's go!
Happy Halloween
作詞・作曲：Junky
Lyrics/Composition: Junky
ねぇ　もう　暗くなりそうだから
Hey, it's already getting dark,
デッチャでもいいかしら
so would it be okay if I come out?
ちょっとね　魔法にかけられた
You know, I've been put under a little magic.
君のお菓子から食べちゃうぞ
I'll start by eating your sweets!
きっと　霧が濃くなるから
The fog will surely get thicker,
みな　集まるかな
so I wonder if everyone will gather?
じっと待って　甘いもの我慢した
I waited patiently and resisted the sweets.
ご褒美を　ほら　きた
Look, here comes my reward!
ひとつ　ふたつ　鐘の音
One, two, the sound of the bell.
騒ぎ出す　小さいオバケたち
The little ghosts are starting to make a fuss.
今日は　許して　くれるのさ
They'll forgive us for today.
さぁ　街に行こう
Now, let's go to the city!
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
イタズラしちゃうぞ ding-dong-dang
I'm going to play a trick, ding-dong-dang!
あっちもこっちも trick or treat
Trick or treat here and there!
キャンディはくれないの？
Won't you give me any candy?
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
いたいけなランタンパンプキン
The innocent lantern pumpkin.
疲れたジャックも踊るよ　朝まで
Tired Jack will dance too, until morning!
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
オバケのカボチャもラララ
The ghost pumpkin too, la la la!
今日は街中 trick or treat
Today, it's trick or treat all over town!
チョコも頂戴よ
Give me some chocolate too!
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
不思議な世界へようこそ
Welcome to the mysterious world!
疲れたジャックも歌うよ　Let's happy halloween
Tired Jack will sing too, Let's happy halloween!
もっと　もっと　ほしがって
Wanting more and more,
欲張りなゴースト
the greedy ghost.
もうない？　それなら
Is there no more? In that case,
イタズラのえじきね
you'll be the victim of a prank!
紅茶じゃない?　いやさ　なんて
Not tea? Oh, no!
言い切りたい　トイレットペーパー
I want to say, toilet paper!
ぐるぐるしちゃえ
Let's spin it around!
今夜はランタン灯してるなら
If the lantern is lit tonight,
甘いの頂戴　さぁ　パーティは終わらない
give me something sweet! The party won't end!
ほら　だって Happy Halloween
Look, because it's Happy Halloween!
時計も回る tick-tack
The clock turns too, tick-tack!
あっちもこっちも trick or treat
Trick or treat here and there!
目もくらむパンプキンパイ
A dazzling pumpkin pie!
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
だから夜更かししちゃうじゃない
That's why we stay up late, don't we?
疲れたジャックも寝ないわ　朝まで
Tired Jack won't sleep either, until morning!
だって Happy Halloween
Because it's Happy Halloween!
今日は Happy Halloween
Today is Happy Halloween!
さぁ　Let's trick or treat
Now, let's trick or treat!
赤いキャンディ転がして
Roll the red candy!
朝まで寝たくない
I don't want to sleep until morning!
今宵はHalloween Night!
作詞・作曲：山崎寛子 / 編曲：河合泰志 (Arte Refact)
Tonight is Halloween Night!
Lyrics/Composition: Hiroko Yamazaki / Arrangement: Taishi Kawai (Arte Refact)
今宵は Halloween Night!
Tonight is Halloween Night!
12時　鳴り響いた教会
At 12 o'clock, the church bells rang.
気づけば　通り過ぎてる
Before I knew it, I'd passed by.
見つけた　摩訶不思議な招待
I found a most mysterious invitation.
逃げたら　お仕置きするぞ
If you run away, I'll punish you!
ほらほら　お菓子を頂戴
Come on, come on, give me some candy!
くれなきゃ　イタズラするぞ
If you don't, I'll play a trick on you!
するぞ
Let's do it
いつでも
Anytime
ほら準備は万端
Look, we're all set
まだまだ
Not yet, not yet
夜は長いさ
The night is long
キミは全然なってない子でしょ
You're not doing it right at all, are you?
まさか様じゃん？ フォールインナイト
Head over heels? Fall in Night
今ならハロウィンナイト
Now it's Halloween Night
ほら悪い子どこかな
Look, where's the bad kid?
捕まえちゃうぞ
I'm gonna catch you
フォールインナイト
Fall in Night
キミは全然なってない子でしょ
You're not doing it right at all, are you?
今ならハロウィンナイト
Now it's Halloween Night
さぁダンシングナイト ほらもっと
Come on, dancing night, look, more
悪魔だって今日はハロー＆トリート
Even devils say hello & treat today
好きにやり合うように
As you like
ほら百鬼夜行に乗ってレッツゴー
Look, hop on the Night Parade and let's go
踊り合おう ほらもっと
Let's dance together, look, more
さぁみんなでみんなでみんなで踊ろう
Come on, everyone, everyone, everyone, let's dance
ジャンボリー ジャンボリー
Jamboree, jamboree
ねぇダンシングナイト さぁ踊ろ
Hey, dancing night, let's dance
お菓子をもっと頂戴 チョコ ＆ トリート
Give me more treats, chocolate & treat
好きにやりたいように
Just as you want to
魔法使いだ空を飛ぼう
We're wizards, let's fly through the sky
締め歌達もさぁ歌おう
Let's sing the finale songs too
今から始まる
Starting now
フォールインハロウィンナイト
Fall in Halloween Night
まだまだ ほらおかしなショータイム
Not yet, look, it's a strange showtime
続きは宵闇の中で
The rest is within the dusk
気づけばもう二度とも戻れない
Before you know it, you can never go back
悪夢で狼が笑う
A wolf laughs in the nightmare
それでは全然なってない君は
So, you're not doing it right at all
まさか様じゃん？ フォールインナイト
Head over heels? Fall in Night
それでは全然なってない君は
So, you're not doing it right at all
まさか様 ハロウィンナイト
Upside down, Halloween Night
それでは全然なってない君は
So, you're not doing it right at all
まさか様じゃん？ フォールインナイト
Head over heels? Fall in Night
それでは全然なってない君は
So, you're not doing it right at all
今ならハロウィンナイト
Now it's Halloween Night
みんな！お菓子の準備はできてるよね？
Everyone! You've got your treats ready, right?
持ってない人にはイタズラしちゃうからね！
If you don't have any, I'm going to play a trick on you!
お菓子の準備ができた人から手を挙げて！
Those who have their treats ready, put your hands up!
イタズラしてほしいの？
Do you want me to play a trick?
食べちゃうぞ！
I'm gonna eat you!
さぁダンシングナイト ほらもっと
Come on, dancing night, look, more
悪魔だって今日はハロー＆トリート
Even devils say hello & treat today
好きに飛び乗るように
As you like to jump in
カボチャの竜に乗って行こう
Let's ride on the pumpkin dragon
全員騎士も乗ってレッツゴー
Every knight get on, let's go
さぁみんなもみんなもみんなも踊ろう
Come on, everyone, everyone, everyone, let's dance
ジャンボリー ジャンボリー
Jamboree, jamboree
サーダンシングナイト さぁ踊ろ
Come on, dancing night, let's dance
おばけたちもほら踊ろ
Look, ghosts are dancing too
陽気な夜をもっと踊るわ
I'll dance through this cheerful night even more
人間たちもほら歌おう
Humans, let's sing too
別の世界からもヤッホー もっと
Say 'Yahoo' from another world too, more
まだ終わらない ジャンボリー ジャンボリー
It's not over yet, jamboree, jamboree
そう夜に囚われた僕らの
Yes, for us, who are captivated by the night
終わらないパーティー
The party never ends
さぁまた始まる
Now, it's starting again
フォールインハロウィンナイト
Fall in Halloween Night
クレイジーナイト！
Crazy Night!
白い雪のプリンセスは
The Snow White Princess is
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall
世界で一番可愛いのは
Who's the cutest in the world?
やめて棘のような視線迫る
Stop it, those thorn-like gazes are closing in
優しいフリした彼女が
She, who pretended to be kind
素敵な晩餐もてなした
Served a wonderful dinner
そっと口に含むと
When I gently put it in my mouth...
笑み
...a smile
薄れゆく
Fading away
意思の中で
Within my consciousness
夢を見てる
I'm dreaming
いつかのおとぎ話
Of a fairy tale from sometime
時が止まる
Time stops
お願いKISSで目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if taking me out of the white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマ的な事情
The hatred that pierces through is a dramatic circumstance
祈っても君はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, you still don't come
あぁ
Ah...
鏡よ鏡よ鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror on the wall
強引にさあ、
Come on, forcefully,
上書きするから
I'll overwrite it,
妬みを買ってしまった
I've incurred jealousy.
7つの小人はいるけど
The seven dwarves are here,
助ける素振り、知らん振りね
but they pretend to help while ignoring me.
そっと首を掴まれ
Gently grabbed by the neck,
笑み
A smile...
一粒の...
A single drop of...
...涙さえも
...even a tear...
拭えなくて
...cannot be wiped away,
呼吸もままならない
and I can barely breathe.
視界 失せた
My vision has faded.
消えそうだから 早く駆けてほしいの
Since I'm about to disappear, I want you to run to me quickly.
訳は聞かないで 応えられない
Don't ask why, I can't answer.
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love.
もうすぐで いなくなるのかな
Will I be gone soon?
途切れてく
Fading out,
命の音
...the sound of life.
毒リンゴを食した
Having eaten the poisoned apple,
少女のように 眠りにつく
I fall asleep like a young girl.
お願い KISSで 目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me up with a kiss.
胸の中の声 届きますか
Can the voice in my heart reach you?
階段を上ったら
If you go up the stairs,
ドアを開けるだけで 見つかるよ
you'll find it just by opening the door.
お願い KISSで 目を覚ましてほしいの
Please, I want you to wake me up with a kiss.
白い柩から 連れ出すように
As if to take me out of the white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみは ドラマティックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic situation.
祈っても 王子様はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince hasn't come yet.
消えてしまう
I will disappear,
その前に
...before that happens.
東京ウィンターセッション
Tokyo Winter Session
ねえ、こっちおいでよ、なんて
Hey, come over here, or something...
えっと、聞こえてますよ、なんて
Um, I can hear you, or something...
1, 2, 3, 4!
冬ですね
It's winter
(さあ、クリスマス！)
(Come on, Christmas!)
どこか行きたい？
Want to go somewhere?
(家でもいいよ)
(Home is fine too)
みんな呼ぼうか？
Should we call everyone?
(二人きりがいいのに)
(I'd rather it be just the two of us...)
冗談だよ、そのつもり
Just kidding, I meant that.
予約したんだ
I made a reservation
(おしゃれなお店)
(at a stylish restaurant)
落ち着かないな
I feel out of place
(無理しちゃったね)
(You pushed yourself, didn't you?)
何頼もうか？
What should we order?
(メニューが読めないです)
(I can't read the menu)
大人になれますか？
Can we become adults?
雪景色、東京都は
A snowy landscape, Tokyo is...
君の目が潤んでいる
...your eyes are moist.
ライトアップが二人の影
The lighting brings our shadows...
想いを近づけた
...and feelings closer.
Please, Please! こっちおいで
Please, Please! Come over here
あげてこうぜ DJ! Party Night!
Let's turn it up, DJ! Party Night!
寂しいなんて言わせない
I won't let you say you're lonely
嫌なことはポイさ、騒ごうぜ
Throw away the bad things, let's make some noise
大好きな人と踊ろう
Let's dance with the one we love
大胆なことしちゃおうぜ
Let's do something bold
急接近は目隠し
A sudden approach is a blindfold
今日こそは想いを伝えて
Today of all days, convey your feelings
新年ですね
It's the New Year
(初バレンタイン)
(First Valentine's)
ちょっと早くない？
Isn't that a bit early?
(頑張れ、私！)
(Do your best, me!)
必要かもね
It might be necessary
(今年こそは完食)
(this year for sure, eat it all)
目指して頑張ります
I'll do my best aiming for that
いいね
Nice.
お願いは何？
What's your wish?
ねえ、秘密だよ
Hey, it's a secret.
おみくじなんて 気にしなくていいのに
You shouldn't worry about fortune slips.
気合いが入ります
I'm getting fired up.
君と初めての朝
My first morning with you.
初日の出染まる君
You, colored by the first sunrise.
オレンジ色輝いて
Shining in orange.
ねえ ねえ
Hey, hey.
触れていたいよ
I want to touch you.
トントン
Knock knock.
こっちおいで
Come over here.
揺らしてよDJ パーティーナイト
Shake it, DJ, Party night!
このままじゃ終われない
It can't end like this.
今だけのチャンス 話そうよ
It's our only chance, let's talk.
明日のことは忘れよう
Let's forget about tomorrow.
今じゃなきゃダメなんです
It has to be now.
急展開を楽しもう
Let's enjoy the sudden turn of events.
今日こそは君に
Today, for sure, to you...
好きだよ
I love you.
Oh oh oh... 君じゃなきゃダメなんです
Oh oh oh... It has to be you.
Oh oh oh...
Please please こっちおいで
Please please, come here.
あげてこうぜDJ パーティーナイト
Turn it up, DJ, Party night!
淋しいなんて言ってない
I'm not saying I'm lonely.
嫌なことはポイさわごう
Throw away the bad stuff, let's party!
大好きな人と踊ろう
Let's dance with the one we love.
大胆なことしちゃおう
Let's do something bold.
急接近は雨上がり
Getting close after the rain.
今日こそは君に伝える
Today, for sure, I'll tell you.
好きだよ
I love you.
気まぐれロマンティック
Kimagure Romantic
ロマンティック 恋のアンテナは
Romantic, the antenna of love...
嵐でどこかへ飛んでいった
...was blown away somewhere by the storm.
嘘でしょ 冷たく知らんぷり
You're kidding, right? Acting cold and indifferent.
こしゃくなエクボにちょっと
That cheeky dimple...
心が揺れてる
...is making my heart flutter a bit.
本当は本気で私を
Honestly, I want you to...
叱ってくれる大事な人
...be that special someone who'll truly scold me.
なんて言ったらあいつは
If I said that, he would...
得意げになるから
...just get all full of himself,
もう褒めたりしない
so I won't praise him anymore.
退屈な運命に飽き飽きしたの
I'm fed up with this boring fate.
知らない言葉で解き放して
Set me free with words I've never heard before.
ねだりだり心の扉を壊してよ
I'm begging you, break down the door to my heart.
大切なことは目を見て言って
Look me in the eye when you say what's important.
あなたとならこの街を抜け出せる
With you, I can escape this city.
今すぐ連れ出して My Sweet Sweet Darling
Take me away right now, my sweet, sweet darling.
ドラマティック 笑顔の秘密を
Dramatic, the secret of that smile...
誰だって探し続けてる
...is what everyone keeps searching for.
見上げた空に描くの
I'll paint on the sky I look up at...
幸せの形
...the shape of happiness.
そう 私らしくいたい
Yes, I want to stay true to myself.
気まぐれなテンションで振り回すけど
I might lead you around with my whimsical moods, but...
★気まぐれロマンティック★
★Kimagure Romantic★
この手はかならず離さないで
Don't ever let go of this hand.
ねぇ
Hey.
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を叩いてよ
Darling, darling, knock on the door of my heart.
素直な気持ちがあふれてゆく
My honest feelings are overflowing.
あなたとならば笑っていられるよ
With you, I can keep on smiling.
今すぐ駆け出すの my sweet sweet darling
I'm running out right now, my sweet sweet darling.
ダーリン ダーリン きっと私はつかめるよ
Darling, darling, I'm sure I can grasp it.
幸せの意味に気づいてゆく
I'm starting to realize the meaning of happiness.
あなたとならば明日を変えられる
With you, I can change tomorrow.
今すぐ連れ出して my sweet sweet darling
Take me away right now, my sweet sweet darling.
ダーリン ダーリン 心の扉を壊してよ
Darling, darling, break down the door of my heart.
大切なことは目を見て言って
Tell me the important things while looking into my eyes.
あなたとならばこの街を抜け出せる
With you, I can escape this town.
今すぐ連れ出して my sweet sweet darling
Take me away right now, my sweet sweet darling.
探しに行くんだ　そこへ
I'm going to find it, over there.
春擬き
作詞：やなぎなぎ　作曲：北川勝利
Harumodoki
Lyrics: Yanaginagi / Composition: Katsutoshi Kitagawa
空欄を埋め　完成した定理
Filling in the blanks, the completed theorem.
正しいはずなのに　ひらり空回り
It should be correct, but it's just spinning in circles.
未来はいびつで　わずかな亀裂から
The future is distorted, and from a small crack...
いくらでもよれて　理想から逸れていくんだ
...it twists and turns, deviating from the ideal.
ぬるま湯が　すうっと冷めていく音がしてた
I heard the sound of lukewarm water quickly cooling down.
道を変えるのなら
If I'm to change my path...
のなら
...if so...
今なら　こんなレプリカはいらない
Right now, I don't need a replica like this.
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
Only something that can be called "genuine" is enough.
探しに行くんだ　そこへ
I'm going to find it, over there.
でもそれは良く出来たフェアリーテイルみたい
But it's like a well-crafted fairy tale.
答えの消えた　空欄を見つめる
I stare at the blanks where the answers have vanished.
埋めたはずなのに　どうしても分からない
I should have filled them in, but I just don't understand.
綺麗な花は　大事に育てても
Even if I carefully raise beautiful flowers...
遠慮ない土足で　簡単に踏みにじられた
...they were easily trampled by unreserved muddy feet.
降り積もる白に　小さな芽覆われていく
The small buds are being covered by the piling white snow.
遠い遠い春は
The far, far away spring...
息の下
...is beneath the breath.
見えないものはどうして　記憶から薄れてしまうんだ
Why do things that can't be seen fade away from memory?
探しに行く場所さえも
Even the place I'm going to find...
見失う僕たちは　気付かず芽を踏む
...is lost to us as we unknowingly tread on the buds.
思い出を頼りに　救ってた花はすぐ枯れた
The flower I saved by relying on memories withered quickly.
足元には　気付かずに　気付かずに
At my feet, without noticing, without noticing...
本物と呼べる場所を
A place I can call real...
（場所を）
(...a place)
探しに行くのはきっと
I'm sure that searching for it...
（きっと）
(...I'm sure)
今なんだ　こんなレプリカはいらない
It's now. I don't need a replica like this.
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
Only things I can call real are enough.
探しに行くから　君を
Because I'm going to find you...
ありがとう　小さな目　見つけてくれたこと
Thank you, for those small eyes finding me.
君は呟いた
...you muttered.
24時間くらい　あれいいのにな
I wish I had about 24 hours...
やり残したことたくさんで　鞄がパンパン
So many things left undone, my bag is bursting.
君をわかりたい
I want to understand you.
君を忘れたい
I want to forget you.
君を守りたい
I want to protect you.
それぞれの願い
Each of our wishes.
海の家！
Beach house!
山の家！
Mountain house!
故郷の家！
Hometown home!
世界周遊　悠久休暇
World tour, eternal vacation.
お天道様を飲み干して
Drink up the sun...
いっせーのーせでもぐり込め
...and dive in on the count of three.
誰ひとり欠けず川をさかのぼれ
Follow the river upstream with no one left behind.
弾む息継ぎ仲間の声
Bouncing breaths, the voices of friends.
踊る　止まらないこの水流と
Dancing with this unstoppable current...
泳いで勝って大丈夫
...swimming and winning, it's okay.
どんなつまずきだって　きっとすべての夏が微笑んで
No matter the stumble, surely every summer will smile.
あんなに早く大人になりたかったのに
I wanted to grow up so fast back then...
そうだろ
Right?
わかんないよ
I don't know.
永遠なんてないさ
Nothing lasts forever,
夏休みだって
not even summer vacation.
数週間煌めき　またひとつの物語
A few weeks of sparkle, another story begins.
まだ納得いかないさ
I'm still not convinced,
油蝉だって
even the cicadas...
3年も持ちこがれて　飛び出したお祭り
...wait for three years for this festival to burst out.
潮風に溶けて　夏に木霊した
Dissolving in the sea breeze, echoing in the summer.
僕らのササマバケーション
Our Sasama Vacation.
海の家！
Beach house!
山の家！
Mountain house!
故郷の家！
Hometown home!
世界周遊　悠久休暇
World tour, eternal vacation.
僕が好きな君が好きなやつは誰が好きなんだい？
Who does the person you like, that I like, like?
多角関係！
Polygonal relationship!
あれあれ何遍転生したって待って何遍？
Hey, hey, no matter how many times I reincarnate—wait, how many?
我々惹かれ合う　海よりも遠い僕らの住処も
We're drawn to each other, even our homes further than the sea...
また時が巡れば思い出すよ　あの青と青の境界線を
When time comes around again, I'll remember that boundary between blue and blue.
皿際覗いて白く雲を
Peeking at the edge of the plate, the white clouds...
来年も再来年も　笑って泣いてみたいなぁ
Next year and the year after, I want to laugh and cry.
お前も！
You!
お供！
Companion!
君も！
You too!
大好きだ！
I love you all!
永遠なんてないさ
Nothing lasts forever,
花火玉だって
not even fireworks.
数秒間煌めき　命燃やす向日葵
Sparkling for a few seconds, sunflowers burning their lives.
まだ納得いかないさ
I'm still not convinced,
学生服だって
even school uniforms...
3年玉送り育ち　押し入れの片隅
...three years of growth, now in a corner of the closet.
共に今　この川下ろう
Let's go down this river together now.
本当はみんな　気づかないふりしてた
Actually, everyone was just pretending not to notice.
この夏には　もう二度と戻れないってことを
That we can never return to this summer again.
24時間くらい　あれいいのにな
I wish I had about 24 hours...
波待ちしたことたくさんで　鞄がパンパン
So many times waiting for waves, my bag is bursting.
君を泣かせない
I won't make you cry.
君を忘れない
I won't forget you.
君を離さない
I won't let you go.
それぞれの誓い
Each of our oaths.
沈む日と共に　水平線に隠した
Hidden in the horizon along with the setting sun.
僕らのササマバケーション
Our Sasama Vacation.
永遠なんてないさ　夏休みだって　数週間煌めき　またひとつの物語
Nothing lasts forever, not even summer vacation. A few weeks of sparkle, another story begins.
まだ納得いかないさ　油蝉だって　3年も持ちこがれて　飛び出したお祭り
I'm still not convinced, even the cicadas wait for three years for this festival to burst out.
永遠なんてないさ　永遠なんてないさ
Nothing lasts forever. Nothing lasts forever.
まだ納得いかないさ　まだ納得いかないさ
I'm still not convinced. I'm still not convinced.
潮風に溶けて　夏に木霊した
Dissolving in the sea breeze, echoing in the summer.
僕らのササマバケーション
Our Sasama Vacation.
元気してるかー？
How are you doing?
ごはん食べれてるー？
Are you eating well?
恋してるぞ！
I love you guys!
その夏は一度きりだ
That summer only happens once
人生で一度きりだ
It's a once-in-a-lifetime experience
だから、いってらー！
So, have a good one!
僕らのラストサマーバケーション
Our last summer vacation
というわけで、アリーナに戻ってきましたよ！
And so, I'm back in the arena!
ただいまー！
I'm home!
はい、今回ですね、夏に始まり、夏で終わる...
Well, this time, I've put together a setlist...
ちょっとストーリー感のあるね、セトリにしていますけど、どうでしたか？
...that starts and ends in summer, with a bit of a story. How was it?
可愛かった？
Was it cute?
うわー、ありがとうね！
Wow, thank you!
ゲストパートもね、もうみんな一緒に歌ってくれて嬉しかったでございますよ！
I was so happy that everyone sang along during the guest parts too!
ちなみに、この配信が終わった後に、メンバー限定のね、
By the way, after this stream ends, there will be a members-only...
あのアンコールライブもありますので、ぜひぜひ見に来てくださいね！
...encore live, so please come and watch it!
ダンスもね、あの本編頑張っておりますので、
I've been working hard on the dancing in the main part, so...
ちょっと、あの感想とかもたくさんポストしてください！
...please post a lot of your thoughts and feedback!
はい、そして、なんと、次が最後の曲になってしまいます。早いねー！
And now, surprisingly, the next one will be the last song. It went by so fast!
はい、最後はなんと... 新曲でございます！やったー！
The final song is... a new one! Yay!
はい、ということで...
Alright then...
タイトルはこちら！ババン！こちら！『ENDLESS FES』でございます！
Here's the title! Ta-da! It's "ENDLESS FES"!
作曲はですね、みんな大好きFAKE TYPE.さんにお願いをしましたよ！
I asked everyone's favorite FAKE TYPE. to compose it!
そしてMV制作はPPPさんでございます！
And the music video was produced by PPP!
この後、11月1日の24時にね、リリースされますので、無限に聞いてください！
It'll be released at midnight on November 1st, so please listen to it on repeat!
もう無限に聞きたくなる中毒性のある曲でございます。
It's an addictive song that you'll want to listen to forever.
なんか、あのまつりすが超リアルなリスになってる、MVで見てみてね！
The Matsurisu look like super-realistic squirrels in the MV, so check it out!
はい、そしてMV公開はこの配信の後にプレミア公開がありますので、
Also, the music video will have a YouTube premiere after this stream,
そちらもお見逃しなく！よろしくチェックワンツー！
so don't miss it! Be sure to check it out!
はい、ということで...
Alright, well...
それでは聴いてください、『ENDLESS FES』！
Now, please listen to "ENDLESS FES"!
ENDLESS FES
作詞：TOPHAMHAT-KYO (FAKE TYPE.)
作曲：FAKE TYPE.
編曲：DYES IWASAKI (FAKE TYPE.)
ENDLESS FES
Lyrics: TOPHAMHAT-KYO (FAKE TYPE.)
Composition: FAKE TYPE.
Arrangement: DYES IWASAKI (FAKE TYPE.)
天を衝いた神輿
A portable shrine that pierces the heavens
フェスティバルンルン 奉り候
A festival full of joy, I humbly offer it
文明開化のお通りです 今日も今日とてあしは上機嫌
Civilization is passing through, today as ever, I'm in high spirits
Let's party, don't panic こっちおいで電脳ジャンキー
Let's party, don't panic, come over here, cyber junkies
WiFi可視化でワイワイはしゃげば 曖昧なことは大体 Whatever
With visible WiFi, let's make some noise, vague things are mostly "Whatever"
接続完了でハイテンション！
Connection complete, high tension!
えんやこら上がれ 総員パワー合わせ
Heave-ho, rise up! Everyone, combine your power
銀河すら凌駕する輝きを
To show a brilliance that even surpasses the galaxy
ほらいっちょ鳴らせ おまけにもういっちょ鳴らせ
Come on, ring it once, and once more for good measure
カルチャーこちゃ混ぜの万華鏡
A kaleidoscope where cultures are mixed together
嗚呼 絶景かな 相も変わらず連綿と豊穣
Ah, what a magnificent view, as always, continuous and fertile
ミームはまるで花火の如し 鮮やかに咲き乱れ散っては刻まれる
Memes are just like fireworks, blooming vividly, scattering, and being engraved
YOU DIED
超超超常現象巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Cause a super-super-supernatural phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないいないポイ
Throw away all the "what-ifs" with a poof
渾々混沌でも舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Dance even through the gushing chaos (Yeah!)
ないものないエンターテインメント 飛び跳ねろ
Entertainment that has everything, jump around
Bounce... baby bounce
とりあえず朝まで 昼夜問わず繋がっちゃおう
For now, until morning, let's stay connected day and night
Oh bounce... baby bounce
感覚サマーバケーションみたいでしょ？ とびきりの Fun time
It feels just like a summer vacation, right? An extraordinary Fun time
今日もいつもの場所から始まる Superb view
Today too, a Superb view starts from our usual place
Look at you 選り取り見取りで供給過多気味
Look at you, spoilt for choice and a bit oversupplied
But you said "Give me give me" It's a part of 生きる意味
But you said "Give me give me", it's a part of the meaning of life
オレンジ色マーマレード 太陽のよう笑え
Orange marmalade, smile like the sun
宇宙すら越え遥か彼方にも
Even beyond the universe, to the far reaches of the distance
ほらいっちょかませ おまけにもういっちょかませ
Come on, show them what you've got, and then some more
ジャンルこちゃ混ぜの Turntable
A Turntable where all genres are mixed together
嗚呼 絶景かな
Ah, what a magnificent view
予測出来ない展開なほど
The more unpredictable the developments are,
みんなの心を鷲掴み 華やかに伝播されてハート満たされる
the more they grab everyone's hearts, spreading vividly and filling them
超超超常現象巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Cause a super-super-supernatural phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないいないポイ
Throw away all the "what-ifs" with a poof
渾々混沌でも舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Dance even through the gushing chaos (Yeah!)
ないものないエンターテインメント 飛び跳ねろ
Entertainment that has everything, jump around
天を衝いた神輿
A portable shrine that pierces the heavens
フェスティバルンルン 奉り候
A festival full of joy, I humbly offer it
勉強も遊びも On the web 気楽に集まり
Studying and playing on the web, gathering casually
国境越えてコラボレート ピースに交わり
Collaborating across borders, mingling in peace
好きなデバイスでご覧あれ 湧き立つ勇気凛々
Watch on your favorite device, courage welling up
もうご立派なネット中毒です あとのまつり (My men)
You're already a full-fledged net addict, Matsuri's after-party (My men)
超超超現象 巻き起こせ (Yeah!)
Cause a super super super phenomenon (Yeah!)
たらればなんていないいないボイ
No such thing as "what ifs"
ゴゴゴッとうねり舞い踊れ (Yeah!)
Dance with a rumbling surge (Yeah!)
何でもありエンターテイメント エンドレスのフェス
Anything-goes entertainment, an endless festival
兎にも角にも目一杯楽しんでね
Anyway, please enjoy it to the fullest!
7回目のおたんじょーび おいわいしてくれて ありがとう
Thank you for celebrating my 7th birthday with me.
まつりがしぬまで 毎年いわえてもらうから かくごしておけよ〜!
I'll have you celebrate every year until I die, so be prepared!